[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
me
knowledge is power
[Music]
really what i wanted to do is we missed
pop culture
on the talk is i obviously i have a like
a more myopic political lens
because it's what's actually important
in the world like effect it actually
affects people
like the political ramifications and
actual pop culture
doesn't at all you know it's just like
so it's just not important to me
and really anyone so i just didn't talk
about it but most people's framework of
cancer culture is jake paul got
cancelled not
trans people don't get rights you know
right yeah so we can reference the other
stuff because we don't have to dump down
everything but yeah i guess we can bring
it back down to like a level of
most people listening to the podcast
don't know who those people are even
what i want to do is just touch on the
pop culture
thing because i want to talk about
accountability
because what i really think is most the
time eighty percent of the time when
somebody gets cancelled it's just
they're being held accountable for
something that they did that's not good
and they don't really like it and now
there's a word to deflect it
right right yeah it's just like people
in power don't like being held
accountable
that's actually why most people acquire
power who gets to choose
who gets to choose who holds people
accountable though
you can't just hand the mic to the
loudest person in the room because
they're
you know they don't like what happened
there's always it's so contextual and
it's so
relative yeah i know but there are some
through lines
with being held like if you just are
doing some blatantly shitty stuff
it's like that's pretty universally
accepted is not
cool like yeah you should be held
accountable like i want to go over brian
cowan and crystal leah
because they both had really weird
reactions to some pretty bad stuff
it's like i would deem pretty obviously
probably true
all things considered and their
deflection was
the mob's coming after me i'm a good guy
it's just canceled culture
but it's like well you have a past of
being pretty aggressive towards women
you verbally talk about it all the time
all your friends talk about this and
there's been like five people you know
that said they've been on the wrong side
of this it's probably true
yeah yeah and it's like now you're being
held accountable and you don't really
like it and it's dangerous for your
career so of course you're going to
deflect it and i think that a lot of the
rhetoric
just in the pop culture sphere comes
around that is i
i've done bad things because i've been
allowed to for a long time and i'm
finally being held accountable i don't
really like it very much
of course i mean nobody would like it
very much but so what's
there is something to be said about the
uh you know the imaginary line that
we'll have to draw though
i mean so what what is deemed dude
that's outlandish that's not okay like
obviously you know uh i think chris
chris was texting underage girls in a
sexual manner obviously that's like okay
cool
not good uh but otherwise where do we
leave room for people
like the things being pulled up from 25
years ago
things being pulled up from when the
person in in question
was an immature or you know lesser than
version of themselves i don't know the
pulling stuff i mean
that's contextual like did you murder
somebody 20 years ago
probably accountability is necessary but
it's like
were you a little unsensitive at work 30
years ago when everyone was and you just
aren't famous so people are talking
about it that's probably not worthy
well there's just no rules to most stuff
like reality is pretty subjective and
most stuff is pretty subjective to be
honest
and it's not
it just requires a lot of um nuance
which i think has been lost upon all of
us
nuance is just something that people
don't like to engage with because it's
hard
do you think that our do you think that
our reactions to a lot of these things
and the way we react and how obtusely
or acutely we react to certain things um
do you think that's disproportionate
like sometimes i feel that
a lot of like a summarization of this
cancel culture stuff
is for me like okay i'm not saying it's
not important like yes let's do that yes
what that person did was wrong yes let's
have some you know reconciliation let's
have some uh
uh repentance i i don't know
whatever but i i'm just always thinking
why the [__] are we talking about this
like why are we like why is this the
main thing
a camera is being pointed at is it
because it's just it's just pop culture
and this is what sells and this is
what's hot this is the hot take
of what's going on now it's like oh
these people if we really put a
magnifying glass on their belief system
it will get us constant things to talk
about um and so our new cycle is kind of
like eating our culture
full circle like why are we paying
attention to this
and not other important things about our
reality and our
you know culture and life um i am
conflicted on the answer to this i think
on one hand
we're kind of force-fed and like just
useless dribble
from media companies just because it
sells
it's easy it's easy outrage you know i
mean it's really just being
monetized to some degree and it's also
easier to confront than
um hey the world's increasing in heat
and everyone
is like gonna die in a hundred years
like that's a lot harder to grapple with
and it's not immediately relevant
so like you can either have an
existential crisis or make fun of jake
paul what do you think
to have a good like you know to have a
good saturday okay i totally agree but i
think that
this is like this is a big [__] deal
then
like like the fact that we're okay
there's this scene in the show with the
good place you've watched a good place
right i think i've asked you this
i have not i do use one line all the
time from the good place but
which is what's the line i can't believe
it's like i can't believe what i'm
talking i'm a total snack
i say that pretty frequently glad you
pulled that out of like you're
you're an amateur philosopher who pulled
that out of a philosophy tv series i
don't know i've seen
one that's the only scene i've seen
you would love it i'm pretty sure that
i've i've mentioned it to you a couple
times i'm annoying about it i'm always
wanting to get people to watch it but
anyway so there's this scene where um
forget the actor's name but phoebe from
friends she's in the show
and they get to the good place uh
spoiler alert they get to like this is
this is a good place you know the
representation in this sitcom of heaven
um and what it is is like they're all
just like chilling
uh one of them one of the main
characters wants to meet phoebe and she
used to be this intelligent
mathematician
um like really like sought after who
would not love to talk to her if you're
into philosophy or mathematics or
science or one of those things and one
of the main characters goes to talk to
her
and she doesn't remember any of that
stuff she's just like drinking
margaritas and it's an infinite party
so it's basically like we're fed
in this good place we get everything we
ever wanted but then eventually we
forget the importance of like oh yeah i
get to be shaped by
you know hardships and um trying to
learn things that are difficult
but when you're when you're alive for
thousands and thousands of years that's
how it is in the good places an infinite
amount like you get to choose basically
when you leave but you're otherwise you
live for as long as you want so after a
couple hundred
couple thousand years you stop focusing
on
um stop focusing
on things that challenge you and so so
the the scene
basically the scene they're trying to
tell like they're trying to tell her
like hey this is this is incorrect like
you guys are like turning into mush
piles of dummy
like you're not this isn't how is this
heaven and the thing is is phoebe kind
of keeps breaking out of it she wants to
tell them like hey
this is actually bad but we keep
forgetting because we keep slipping
right back into the divot of like oh
here's another margarita because you can
literally just snap your fingers and
there's a margarita or whatever you want
in your hand
so after a while they get numb to it and
phoebe's not able she kind of
periodically breaks out of it in the
show
but i think that this one i'm pointing
at is
like could we be so numbed that we are
not able to steer our ship
in the right directions you know where
we're focusing on the wrong things and
it could have
semi-catastrophic uh you know answers in
in
in results but it's such a scary thing
it puts us into such a fear response as
a biological human
that is difficult for regular people to
talk about yeah i think that um
this is about to touch on a bunch of
stuff that i want to talk about today
so on one hand it's just i think the
innate powerlessness
of all of it probably makes it hard to
confront one because it's just like
even if you come to the realization that
everything is not how it ought to be
uh you can't really immediately change
it and i think that that
drives a lot of anxiety one two it's
just
hard to look at your own um philosophy
or your own
what is the perspective i guess belief
systems yeah
yeah so you can either spend your
saturday night after you've worked 80
hours
and um dig in or you can ingest some
mindless content and one is infinitely
easier and it will always it usually is
chosen especially in western societies
so although i don't live like that
usually i spend a lot of time toiling
and i
i like i think it's fun to be challenged
just like this constant iron sharpens
iron i just need to come to
like better conclusions with more
information but sometimes i just like to
play video games as well so like i
totally i totally get it but it can't we
can't live in the state of
inundation or inoculation
i agree but so as we're studying these
things like as you're spending your time
as someone who just enjoys philosophy
we're having these conversations it's
hard to wonder what do we do with it
what like what are we really doing like
what what is a podcast what is it trying
to accomplish
what what are long-form conversations
what is like hours of you listening to
like your favorite philosophers or
perspectives hours of me doing the same
in my realm
like it seems like there's something
there that needs to be implied and it
kind of feels important i don't know if
it's this grandiose like
self-importance that's just sneaking in
there but it feels like
more people need to be shifting their
conversations around
um you know kind of the uncomfortable
and less around
the numb margaritas i kind of just think
this is what politics is
politics is where philosophy meets
reality and everything is kind of
innately political
disrespectful to philosophy to me for
some reason well i i mean
usually i would assume at least for me
i'm not gonna i guess i won't assume for
anyone else but
i originally just got into philosophy in
college
i really enjoyed it and then you work
down the line you go from like socrates
to plato and you eventually get to like
heggle and marx and like all these um
unorthodox thinkers from other places
that are not
don't really have western ideas and uh
it's just innately really political
like hannah arendt so you just get to a
point in which the philosophy can no
longer be
political because it kind of never was
after epistemology all of this is
hey i am constructing a worldview or a
tool or a way to think that it should be
applied to make the world as good as it
can be and what is politics
hypothetically it's just a belief system
or a set of rules and values to
maximize human um
capabilities and uh freedom i think
that it's supposed to be that but it if
we look more closely it's not that and
we need to be able to adjust
course right like we need to be able to
realize like hey this thing that we made
to create
like um order amongst chaos basically
uh it worked it's been working it is
great
but we're now it's now in a trajectory
that
may not be great so we might need to
adjust course like how do we
well i think that that's what i was
getting at is i've always thought that
the end goal
of uh engaging in all this philosophy
and all the political thought and all
the rhetoric
is to eventually come to a conclusion
with a clean enough and presentable
enough
a series of talking points that uh you
could go
um gather or rally people for like a
real cause because that's where
the rubber meets the road right so like
if i can figure
if you can precisely figure out a world
view that is going to be optimal for
most people
that is um that catchy enough that you
think will maximize
human um oh i'm looking for a word and i
can't find it
uh satisfaction is not the word i'm
looking for but we'll take it
but i see where you're pointing though
yes yeah so that's where the rubber
meets the road and i don't think it's
always that
but if you look at the political
landscape
there is definitely some side of it that
is pretty egalitarian and wants
to make people's lives better and then
others just
funnel control into more authority and
we have way too much of the latter and
not enough of the former
and i think that that's we're really
running into problems
yeah i think you're right i okay let's
back out of the hole a little bit
let's let's um let's actually
go real far back let's do will you give
a brief
background of like what you like the
classes that you've taken
and kind of like your thinking around
this and then you can kind of present
your
first sort of summarizing claim and then
we'll go through those bullet points
that we had
on for cancer culture yeah
yes or just but but also i mean i think
just as a
as a person who's involved in philosophy
like like why why are you
having perspective about it why is this
interesting to you how does that relate
to the things that studies
so let's see my logic chain
well i took a lot of let's see i've
taken philosophy of religion i've taken
basically i've taken every philosophy
class at uh
the community college where we live and
i've taken a few at
university but most of my study have has
come outside of that and most of it has
been um
usually on metaphysics
epistemology and political philosophy
so i'm really interested in uh
the systems that we put in place to uh
make everyone's life better and what is
a better way to
to make a more egalitarian society how
do we maximize human liberty
and human freedom while also securing
just basic
rights and that's kind of
the pipeline i've gone down i really
like um
a lot of thinkers of modernity i like
marx's work is great
uh modern thinkers i really like slavoy
zijak he's a hegelian
and obviously i like hegel a lot
so let's see i really like
camus for epistemology who really just
talks about
um the absurdity of the world i mean
it's just kind of like this
meaningless thing and it's just this
constant struggle to find meaning and
something that doesn't have meaning
inherently
you see absurd absurdism yeah
and then i really like jean-paul sartre
as well i've read a lot of his work
so cool so that so those all influence
your thinking i mean and i think
i just bringing it back again to the
average listener someone who doesn't
really study philosophy that
it's like it's fascinating to them but
maybe they haven't very much um
to you what does it point out like in
our psyche about our society
like why would it be important to study
philosophy like how does it relate to
our everyday lives how does it a
holistic
approach to like solving problems well
there's a macro and micro sense to this
so on one hand on an individual level
you really just
can um what's the main goal it's how do
i figure out how to live the best life
possible
what are the series of ideas that i can
collect and implement
to just live and be as good as i can be
and just be a good person and that's
like um
a lot of the baseline older philosophy
is
how to think how to analyze the world to
try to stop unconscious bias
like how do you how do i perceive
reality and it's
how can i change that for the better and
then on a macroscopic sense
a lot of the thinkers that i just listed
talk about power dynamics
uh economics and things that really
equate to how the world runs and how it
could definitely be different
so that's what i'm most interested in
now because there's just like an innate
and very large amount of suffering that
goes on due to the systems that are
in place and uh changing them because we
made them up
seems to be of the utmost importance so
i spend a lot of time
especially studying power dynamics
because if you can understand power
dynamics you can understand a lot of
situations a lot clearer like
because it's it just that's how systems
work it's this funnel of power and
things push and pull so if you can take
a step back
understand the system you then have the
capability to change it
and a few of the ideas i want to talk
about later when we get a little down
into the weeds
are clarifications on some schools of
thought or tools used that actually just
assess power dynamics
okay well so how does how does this
bring us back into
cancel culture like what is what is
cancel culture
what are we i'm like like why would we
need to talk about it because i mean
this podcast really has never been
a place where we just talk about hot
topics like i mean when kova came around
i had a couple episodes around that but
obviously
you know that's because it's right in
the forefront of of what's going on we
didn't know what else to do we're trying
to solve problems but
why would it be mentioned here um
like why is it something we should be
focusing on when it comes to you know
mental health
philosophical thought contemplation
well i just i think it's important to
talk about because there is a lot of
fear mongering that goes on
i think people are a lot more frightened
of it than uh is duly necessary
i've talked to many people usually
people that are probably apolitical
or just um see it in the periphery of
social media
you see it like when jake paul gets
canceled or whatever and it's
frightening
because the thought of hey i might do
something wrong and be unaware of it and
now
hundreds of people are gonna brigade me
on twitter and i'm not gonna be able to
participate in society
sounds really scary but it just doesn't
happen it's just not it just doesn't
happen it doesn't happen to really
anyone
so i first off want to liberate people
from being scared of that
but there's obviously a lot more nuance
to this than that
because it seems to be in the collective
psyche of at least americans
this cancel culture idea
this this thing that's happening because
i mean it's
um blasted on news sites usually
maliciously in a lot of ways i find
like it just has a way to deter from
real criticism
but it seems to be talked about
a very lot so i think it's worth talking
about because people think about it a
lot
right yeah i think it's worth you know
consulting because i think we came to
the conclusion
uh with our little brainstorm session
even and even before we hit record that
after kind of mulling it over for a
while it really is this silly glanceable
like
jesus this is not important actually
like this is something that
no regular person should be you know
worried about like no like we shouldn't
worry about but because
we are always protecting our you know
our ego of course but now we have this
like ego 2.0 we have our avatar online
um do you think like our big fear
towards it is a response to like how
quickly and how like difficult it must
be
for us as just humans to adjust to this
entirely new way of thinking and doing
and having this whole new overlay of
reality just
within the last what 15 years i mean
yeah that makes sense it's just an
innate survival response so just the
prospect of
just being completely ostracized from
society because you said
you said something improperly that you
weren't aware of like just out of sheer
actual ignorance not like willful not
bad um not in bad faith
it's just you said a wrong thing and now
you don't get to participate with us
like that like you got kicked out of the
tribe and i that's frightening
explain why that's frightening like i
know you like just pitch and hold that
because i just want to like whoever is
actually sitting here in some sort of
fear like they haven't really thought
about it this
in depth but they're like dang hopefully
nobody pulls up my you know snapchats
from six years ago
yeah well okay so let's run them back we
used to live in uh small communities
tribes uh hunter gatherers and if you
don't
conform to society or fit in with all
these people you will be ostracized
and die because you can't eat because
you're alone you're not gonna be able to
survive we
are collective animals by nature and we
need others to live and i think that
this sparks something just deep inside
people
that they just you don't want to get
kicked out you don't want to get kicked
out of the end group you want to be a
part of the stuff you don't want to do
anything wrong and i think it causes a
lot of unnecessary fear
because it's um i just it's a non-issue
i mean how many people do you personally
know that have been actually affected by
this and i know this is not definitive
i don't know anybody too i don't think i
know anybody who's been like
cancelled this is good i just feel like
if like the simplest answer
is just i mean if okay so say you're
like afraid of getting canceled or
someone comes up to you and they're like
hey what's up with this and they show
you
they walk up to you at a bar right in
your face they're like hey here's a
screenshot if you do remember here's a
picture of you bubba so you said this or
you blackface or you whatever
like all you have to do is go
oh yeah that was kind of [__] up i
didn't really think about that at that
time but yeah
i'll probably do that again like like if
if you genuinely or i mean if it's
something really bad obviously there
needs to be some sort of repentance
so there's a fine line but i think the
average person who's just
living experience trying to figure out
life trying to deal with their own
[__] that they were handed from
childhood like
as long as you know maybe we should
narrow back down on like
when is cancelled culture actually good
like how is it helpful
but again reiterating the average person
has nothing to worry about like we're
all growing we're all adapting nobody's
going to dig up your past and
define you as an entire person through
that yeah
and i as we go along this i actually
want to make a differentiation between
uh how this is viewed in political light
and how this is viewed in pop culture
and i think we'll
start with the latter because it's just
not as large of a topic
so i i firmly believe that celebrities
getting cancelled
most the time is for pretty irrelevant
stuff
like uh usually like doing some
not so fun sexual acts you know just
like actual crimes
or really bad things socially that we
can all kind of agree on and i think now
that there's this fun word that they get
to deter
all criticism for it's like all right so
brian callan is a comedian and i wasn't
going to drop his name in case anyone
liked him i was going to drop at the end
but i think i'll just go through with it
um
so he has a long history of being like
self-describe himself as very aggressive
towards women just like
just having predatory behavior and it
never seemed really that bad until
um hindsight uh he all his friends have
also
corroborated on this and he's had like
four to five female colleagues also
cooperate this
and he had some sexual allegations that
were pretty unsavory come out and uh he
deflected with just
it's cancer culture it's the woke mom
but it's like realistically
these are probably true if you like look
at all of this in hindsight and you're
just being held accountable for it
because you've been in a place of power
and you've been allowed to act like this
and uh
now once you finally have consequences
you just have a you just have it now
like uh it's the woke mob you know none
of my own behavior did any of this it's
just people don't like me and they're
coming after me and i understand
this is subject to a lot of nuance and
subject to a lot of um
it's very case case-dependent but
sometimes people are just being held
accountable they don't really like it
very much
but okay so we do see how we're
in that sense we're going to allow a
sense of authority outside the law right
like so we we have a checks and balances
system of like when people step out of
line or they do something wrong you know
it's called it's called law it's called
the justice system that sort of thing
but
this is kind of a different entity of
it's canceling your
your social not just social praise but i
mean i guess it is someone's livelihood
and
yeah and i like average people can have
that power
all the time although sometimes they
need it so it is kind of a [__] up
well it's how do you deal with it
because society is self-auditing and
this power was given by people in the
first place by social praise
so i could never ask a group of people
to not
to just like keep keep praising this
person because
the loss didn't say not to you know like
you
you i guess you live by the sword you
die by the sword which is really not
how i wanted to be all the way i think
we do have a justice system
for uh reasons but if you've garnered
your whole like life and career on this
social praise and gathering followers
and being a certain way and you are
found to be a completely
different way and actually quite the
contrary to how you presented yourself
i think that's warrants to not receiving
praise anymore
because like why should people praise
you yeah but again you said
how you present yourself and i think
that is way more complicated nowadays
than we
really understand like this social media
thing this internet thing
has really changed like you can have an
empire you can have
i've dealt with it too like i'm always
like how am i being um
inauthentic like how am i focusing too
much on this side of me
and my social media like how am i
digging out these these
oh i want to make sure everybody sees
these things this is exactly what the
ego loves to do
like let's make sure i'm presented in
this way and then these things like
that's real though like they're both
real and valid
i guess we can't just we can't define
people completely off of who they put
themselves out to be because then we're
just
we're just confusing what's really going
on yeah leaving room for it
i think this is definitely different
because um
one you're thinking about this and two
it's not like you just got caught being
kind of mean to a clerk sometimes
like there's like a lot of sexual
assault allegations
that's like that's like way different
that's way different and you
if you ever look around at any of the
like public figures that caught just
they're just being [__] literally
nothing happens it's only it's usually
only real consequences happen when like
real and definitive
like claims are made i'm not saying that
um
i don't think the justice system should
just deal with this and i do think that
some people get thrown under the bus for
this but that is just how it's been
forever and this is not really a new
thing that's happening
yeah like society self-auditing itself
is just
happens and it always has happened we
just have a word for it now
yeah i guess that's true i mean
i don't know i don't want to dive down
the hole of censorship right now but
that's that's what i'm thinking about
about how it does open the door to
certain people saying what's wrong or
right outside of the
the authority of our law yeah but i mean
we've come to terms
the fact that the authority doesn't
actually care what's right or wrong
either though
so we're just having a systemic failure
yeah okay really
like like i mean
who looks for the government for their
morality nobody nobody looks at any
governing body to say this is the way i
need to live life
so that already doesn't this is because
god's dead this is because god is dead
yes nietzsche said it not sorry yes
and i think i said it was freud the
other day yeah nietzsche said that and
it wasn't a happy sentence
yeah no i know and we killed him and
he's like now
how are we gonna arrive at meeting yeah
i mean
oh man that gets so complicated i think
that's just too far into the weeds if we
dive into
what we're both pointing at um
so so let's go back to your notes and
see where we're at all right well i
just want to first stop this album
letters just don't be scared of this
don't worry about it you don't need to
spend any conscious time being
frightened of this
if you genuinely just make an effort to
be pretty inclusionary
just like a good just like a good person
and want to understand
nothing bad is going to happen to you of
any real consequence other than maybe
somebody being mad at you on twitter
which that happens to everyone for any
reason because it's
uh the worst place
i agreed let's see and then i wanted to
talk about um
uh political cancer culture or just how
it is um
portrayed in politics okay yeah so we
covered kind of a pop culture lens a bit
so
which i really am pretty disinterested
in because i just don't feel like the
impacts of pop culture
in this space are that matter that much
they don't affect anyone
but in the political space using a lot
of this rhetoric
can revoke people's rights or their path
to um
having freedom is things like that like
just it's it's fundamentally an obstacle
for human rights in a lot of ways
and just the way it's used so let's see
yeah i really believe that um although
there were maybe about five
six years ago there were some cases in
which
that a mob probably did some pretty
unreasonable stuff i
like to say when brett weinstein got ran
off of um
evergreen that like that is probably the
height but this is like such a minute
small thing that happened that is being
like
blown up to basically anyone that holds
any kind of leftists or liberal values
especially in academia
is now engaged trying to cancel all of
society
and uh all of the things they're saying
are just anti-human rights stuff like
that
i think this is a red herring because
the the core tenants of a lot of these
ideologies
actually are really egalitarian and
inclusionary they want
the working class to have more rights
more free time like these are a lot of
the
tenants and things that are studied
through the
tools that these people use
philosophically
so when i see the opposition
to these people that really just want
things to stay the way they are
use a lot of this rhetoric like
trans bathroom bills or just anything
that is like
meaningless dribble and say cancel
culture they use the term woke a lot
like these are buzzwords
is really just in complete opposition to
um reforming voting rights for black
people
getting uh redlining gone
uh actual trans rights stuff like that i
see it used in opposition to
people being liberated pretty frequently
yeah so i mean
i i hate to repeat what i had said
before about the canary in the coal mine
um you're also using the the terminology
red herring so we're just a couple of
dumb birds but
uh like to
to brett to brett and those guys who
were involved in it
it wasn't i mean obviously it was a big
deal to them because it was their
livelihood and even with the
um you know censorship it still is
affecting their livelihood they were
making money on youtube and they're
being demonetized on youtube um so there
is like obviously a personal stake in it
so i do totally like hear that bias but
some i i think after like diving in
pretty good depth on on what happened
with the evergreen thing
and what what goes on in places like
clubhouse and stuff
is what these guys are talking about
is hey we see it's a we see the writing
on the wall sort of thing like hey
what is being taught to our young people
at a young age
is now catching up to us and the people
who are making the calls and teaching
the young kids
now like this the teachers are
they they have incorrect belief systems
and by that i mean um uh
like they're they're missing something
they don't that
something they're they're doing or
something they're um
a way they're perceiving the world
around them is
dangerous to the collective like it
doesn't have
long term um like we can't we can't
constantly think like this or
eventually after a course of however
many years it's going to crash and burn
i think that's kind of where they're
coming from
when they're making this cancer culture
when they're making this stuff a bigger
deal
what do you think about it yeah i'm not
really trying to i'm not throwing shade
i just think that their personal
experience have uh caused them to
maybe blanket over blow a lot of like
overlook a lot of really
good stuff that and for some hedge cases
you know like a lot of the things and
wishes of these groups of people that
don't quite have such hyper-specific
values or ideas
or aren't the really loud minority you
know that are just like super
authoritarian and like
have a really specific worldview that
you must bend the knee to
like most of the ideology that comes out
of
these philosophies is not like that it's
really inclusionary by nature it's kind
of how they got there which is
very paradoxical and i actually have a
note how i want to talk about how it's
very weird that some people came to
these conclusions but
i just think you're throwing the baby
out with the bathwater and we can talk
about academia if you want
now but yeah i mean let's let's dip our
toes in because i think um
i mean i think just really quick an
overview just the the way that i want to
think about this
is you know our
we all have our own individual reality
we all face of our based off of our
experiences our upbringing um we you
know
what we're taught who are around all
these things they create a belief system
and that's how we perceive reality and
we're all very much
living in a different reality but we're
trying to come to some medium of a
shared reality
and the it's not just like
because i think a lot of times when we
talk about these things it's like okay
harvard is teaching
this class which is real bad and it's a
dumb way of thinking and blah blah it's
like
well we need to make sure harvard's held
accountable and it's like that's not
what we're talking about it's
it's not it's not the blame game it's
not who's the bad person here it's
a like hey how are we misinterpreting
what's really going on how can we take
these conversations that are like
people riding in the streets and people
yelling and blah blah and how can we
like be
not dumb apes about this for a damn
second and solve these problems
in a way that's like cordial and
intelligent and we get the actual
correct people
in to have conversations and we have the
long long conversations even if it takes
months or years like this is how
the you know like like the constitution
these sorts of things are formed by
a group of people saying hey if we
continue to go down the path we're going
down we're just going to keep killing
each other with clubs
and so let's do some sort of
organization let's have some sort of
agreement
blah blah blah and we're not doing that
we seems to be
either we're in the early stages of it
and we're calling it too early or
the this problem that's coming up we're
handling it in stupid
weird yelling at each other from across
the street ways yeah i want to bring up
the fact that a lot like
a lot of people with a lot of money do
really well
making sure things stay the way they are
so when people spend a lot of money to
agitate against all these ideas that are
taught in classrooms that are actually
benign by nature they're tools of
thought
and what you do with them obviously can
be bad just like anything but
innately they just create a more
systemic and holistic view of reality
that can lead to some pretty interesting
findings
but a lot of there is a lot of people a
lot of money to benefit
things by things being the way they are
so they spend a lot of money to rail
against what's going on in academia in a
lot of ways
and even academia is really not that
problematic i firmly believe that the
only
times it could be is with adjunct
professors who teach
some really niche human humanities
courses so like um
by adjunct i mean they're not tenured so
they can be fired so if you have a lot
of
young like really young people coming
into college and they have this
very very strong opinion about something
and it's really hyper specific
uh it's actually better for you to just
go along with it than to teach what you
were going to teach or
deny what they're saying or even combat
them because you don't want the backlash
of being fired and this is actually my
number one biggest problem
with all of the cancel culture is
because it's anti-workers rights in
colleges
because you have adjunct professors that
must bend the knee this is a very nice
scenario by the way this doesn't really
happen
i mean i've it's it's very rare that
this goes on
but um just basically can be steamrolled
by
whatever the people in their class think
because they're
subject to being fired i think that
that's
uh not good i'm gonna go with not good
but i as a whole don't think academia is
a problem at all in fact i think it is
actually
causing a lot of friction and the way
that things are
and is leading things in the way they
ought to be and i don't think a lot of
people
with a lot of power really like that
because they lose money
so if all of these ideas lead
young people to understand that workers
are exploited
um everything is pretty subjective when
we made all these systems and they're
subject to change
and um like a lot of people we've done
america
and just like a lot of the systems in
place are not meant to help people
they're meant to
basically subjugate them so if you can
go
and read about all these philosophies
and learn these things you can come to
these conclusions and that is
not really stable for people trying to
make billions of dollars
right so i think that on the whole
academia is extremely important for the
populace to come to some more
egalitarian
worldviews because in america we
like our textbooks are basically
propaganda they don't actually tell
reality everything we learn up until
college
is just whatever the government wants to
show you and then you finally get a
chance to engage with some ideas that uh
maybe even criticize the way things are
and you realize that things are not how
they ought to be and this is not a
utopia
like hey maybe we've done some things
badly and that causes a lot of agitation
and that can lead to um some friction
i think that's kind of where we're at
yeah
i i do think uh
yeah i do think it does create this i
don't know if it's like
shadow is the right word really but it
does create some sort of like blind spot
in our collective
unconscious though when it comes to like
like if you if we knew 100 certainty
that within three months there was an
asteroid that was going to impact the
earth and we'd all be dead
like we would we would be doing things
and acting differently like we would be
we would be trying to solve gosh i don't
know
where am i trying to go with it
we
we seem to be like we're we're
distracted by these dumb things when
there is
bigger deals going on and it seems like
that is a very important thing and the
reason why we're it's not only that
we're distracted but
when it comes to observing these things
they do
cause like a psychological like there's
it's like a blip it's like
like oh that's [__] scary like really
diving into you know like the concept of
john vervicky's meaning crisis
when you really like feel that and you
really think about i think we have a lot
of
young people who probably are in this
state of like jesus man this world is
[__] like we
are being handed this poo-poo platter
and we have no idea what to do with it
and i think that's where a lot of this
is kind of stemming from and it's it's
psychologically you know destabilizing
to the point of
we don't seem to be able to even come to
uh
agreeance on how we should approach the
problem so we're kind of just fighting
at each other over it yeah
i mean i think most people aren't going
to inspect any of their worldview
that's just kind of how the world is and
how it's always been
so when you get young people that feel
this anxiety
and they go to a place and then they
read all these uh different philosophies
from many different schools of thought
um and realize like hey there's a lot of
problems
and guess what people have been thinking
about this for hundreds of years
actually a lot of people
and maybe uh we're not so powerless to
do something anyways and then you go
try to figure it out and um you realize
it's way bigger than you
so i see this happen a lot and this is
another symptom of
using tools and properly and i feel like
this is semi-paradoxical
but usually all these
philosophical ideas have
people be inclusionary so it's like hey
we need to basically like genders a
social construct or so is race
essentially and we need to collectively
come together because we all have shared
interests
and ask for more rights and liberty we
need to break down these barriers but
it takes a lot of logic and in just like
philosophical pondering to get to this
end point
and when you come out of college you're
just like hey gender is a social
construct
race isn't real and everything that you
think is concrete in the world probably
isn't true
people that didn't have that experience
uh that's
super frightening because like this
relativity and fluidity is really only
present in the minds of people that have
studied philosophy
or gone to studies because most people
look at the world really black and white
this is true this is false this is how
it is
these can't be changed this is the
structure we're living in it
so to just you get one person at the
literal end of this thought process
talking to people that have did not
engage in it
is going to cause some conflict because
it has required a lot of thought to get
there
it requires a lot of explaining and i
think that that's why we can't get on
the same page
just because we have extremely shared
interest but we can't come to realize it
because we haven't had the same exposure
to ideas
and i think that is where we get a lot
of friction with the college students
because i'm i actually agree with most
of the tenants that come out of there i
mean a lot of them
do sometimes in an act to control their
environment take a really hyper specific
world view
and then force it on others and so
instead of being inclusionary you're now
insulating yourself which is the
opposite of what you believe somehow
i think that's bad philosophy but on the
whole these ideas are supposed to bring
the working class together
like really like that's that's the goal
is we want more rights we want people to
not be exploited
right right well so
how do we i mean because now everybody
has
you know yeah we all have a phone but we
all like really looking at what a phone
is and what it does to
our society and what it does to to
humans like we do all have access now
like
like you said the people at the end of
this wire are now able to talk to the
people at the very front
and this is this is unusual like so it
is a
not necessarily just um don't miss
misconceive the
the words that i'm using for lack of
better terms but like
the intelligence of like the many
is way different than the intelligence
of the few and um
intelligence just lack lack of better
words it's basically like like you can
understand when you study this stuff it
actually changes your world view like
it's actually very profound to change
your world
view to have your perspective like be
actually fluid and not just i'm living
out the things that i was taught from
when i was born to when i was seven
years old
and that's exactly what i'm gonna do
until i'm dead but like when you really
question
um what's going on and what we're all
doing here it it
uh it flips around your beliefs yeah
it's the deconstruction of social
constructs
really because you go to a place and you
realize that hey maybe everything's a
little more fluid than i thought and not
everything's so concrete and when you go
talk to somebody that's like lives in
rural alabama and they've lived in their
hometown i know this is like
probably stereotyping but yeah i know
it's i so i apologize but i just want to
drive the no hold on
i've seen a very small piece of reality
and never had any of these things
challenged these two things clashing
don't make
good together they're too far apart i'm
not saying that one person is smarter
than the other
one has just been exposed to more ideas
and had more time to
develop this like this skill i guess
because i don't think that this is just
like people that go to college are way
smarter than others because it's not
true
that's not true at all it's just they've
been exposed to these ideas and now we
have a big rift in world views
and we're just really grasping or
running up against the problems of that
but i do want to talk about some of the
ideas
that are really slandered
uh in the public space that get taught
and they don't necessarily even get
get taught in most college courses you
got to remember college are for-profit
they make money they teach capitalist
economics
and most of the wings are just how to go
be a business person
so like this is not even a big part of
all just like 10
of people that go to college or actually
expose a lot of these ideas
but i want to talk about marxism
intersectionality
post-modernism and critical race theory
because these are big scary words talked
about by
some pretty smart people that i really
think fundamentally have missed the mark
on adequately assessing them elaborate
so let's see what i want to start with i
guess i want to start with
intersectionality because the whole
metoo movement happened
and people were really mad about
feminism for a while i mean because
a lot of men especially young men is
really scary you know
it's like this is not the class of
people you're part of and they
like you see on twitter that somebody
tweets that they hate men
but intersectional studies is the study
of you take a group of people
that is uh just in the hierarchy of
society let's say women
they're technically not at the top that
would be white men that's
that's who reigns supreme in in
intersectional studies and just in
general if you look around
but by using intersectional thought you
go look at other groups of people in
reference to your own and the whole
power spectrum the whole system
and you see their struggles and how they
intertwine with yours
and now you get this interwoven lens of
hey
this is pretty complex and by taking a
different
like analytical lens to other protected
class of people or even
not protected classes of people we can
come to a shared understanding of what
needs to be done to
remedy this so in third wave feminism
with intersectional thought
you actually have many feminists who
really study this come to realize that
men suffer
under the patriarchy as well and i know
it's a big the patriarchy is a big scary
word but
you have really hyper enforced masculine
values you're not allowed to show
emotion
and uh it caused you it just caused a
lot of problems and until you use an
intersectional lens
feminism couldn't come to that
conclusion that these people also suffer
so now it's shared now we have a shared
understanding of reality and how we all
are not benefiting from society
and it just comes to better conclusions
that aren't so insular so you don't just
have one group of people like hey
we want this everyone else in the way
it's just like a it's a nice melding and
people have tried to call
intersectionality the oppression
olympics
which i mean that doesn't really make
sense to me
like in hindsight right it's like if you
look at that like you've come to a
profound conclusion with this tool
that has shown you that what you thought
was the enemy is actually an ally and
suffering as much as you
and now we can go forward together
because we've intersectionally analyzed
this
okay i like that i think that's a good
explanation what uh
we can just go into marxism keep going
uh so marxism
is the big scary word because of the
ussr
um this is pretty hyper complex but the
actual
tenets of marxism is you get the
fundamental idea
of there is a group of people that own
stuff
in a group of people that work that
don't own stuff this is the bourgeoisie
and the proletariat that is
like marx's terms and before
uh industrialization happened if you
were a cobbler if you made shoes
you made the whole shoe this is your
life's work and you
saw it go to fruition you sold them to
somebody this is very fulfilling
okay when factory owners built the
factory you made
shoe holes and you you poke the holes in
shoes you never saw where they went
you are completely alienated from this
whole process and now the profits
that this person that just owns stuff
makes
you don't get most of it instead of
getting all of it so it's
exploitative the way that society
instructors have exploited it because it
separates the worker from the means of
production
like i do the work but i don't control
the means to do so
somebody else does so that is kind of
how
marxists think that like billionaires
happen
ceos happen jeff bezos is exploiting
workers
by extracting money out of them their
labor value is the term
because he's making way more money off
them than they are
than they are getting and ollie does his
own things and
marxists don't think that that is a good
way to structure society because it
doesn't maximize human liberty
yeah yeah because it's kind of like uh
you know billionaires are the winners of
capitalism and we're the losers we don't
like that
is that one yeah they just won and it's
just
it doesn't seem to me to be a good idea
to structure society in a way
that five goblins get to control 95
of the wealth like we live in a
post-scarcity society
like we have enough food and resources
for everyone to live more than a good
life
on the whole planet like unquestionably
and yet
we have starvation in the richest
country in america
like so fundamentally even if you
disagree with the means in which
the marxism will like fix the solution
the problem that they've analyzed is
very
real and using marxist analysis
not saying that you're a marxist is a
really good tool to understand the power
dynamics in society
okay yeah so i'm not saying it's
flawless because obviously this is an
ideology
that was made from a dude that lived a
very long time ago and it's subject to
change and this is all very fluid
but this will lead me in my next thing
is
post modernism is an idea
well a sequence of ideas that seeks to
look at different
uh world views so all the things i've
talked about before post-modernism does
it seeks to mend all these tools and
philosophies together to come to
the greatest physical medic conclusion
they can
to figure out how to structure a better
society so they'll use marxist analysis
they'll use intersectionality they'll
use critical race theory
which is just the study of how systems
impose non-egalitarian outcomes
through power dynamics so it's like
benign right there's nothing evil about
this it's just a tool of analysis
it's not scary and it's not actually
taught in that much schooling
how do we how do we allow
you know with intention how do we allow
these tools or these
you know belief systems like like how do
we get to a point where we can agree
on on one that's going to work for
everyone like i mean that's i know
that's ridiculous because
actually don't do it with america but i
don't think that any one system is going
to work in any one
all places but don't you think we're
going to eventually need some sort of
mutual agreement agreement of sorts like
i mean potentially worldwide like if
we're really thinking into the future
or like because we're seeing now that
what we are what we've become
is a species that's able to control the
future of the planet control the future
of
all the other species and we need i feel
like we need once we notice that and
once we're like
oh damn okay now we have awareness of
how powerful we really
are like let's look at our like we i
wish we could just
pause everything pause society like stop
time and just like okay
what what are our tools where are we at
right now
what could we do that's going to assure
our you know
mutual non-demolition within the next 25
years
well i think that this is sincerely
problematic because i actually think
that modern socialism solves this
because it just doesn't uh aggregate so
much stuff so if the world's on fire
climate change is real
the people in charge that are over
producing want it to stay the same they
want to break epa guidelines they want
as little regulation as possible they
want the world to be on fire
so because they make money when you say
socialism do you
uh i i would like to point out that i
imagine a lot of people in the audience
have a
very large maybe preconceived notion of
what socialism is like what the media
has been painted
what the media has said socialism means
versus what
like its true potential is um yeah so if
you go
it's just a more egalitarian way to form
society so if
right now in a capitalist society we
over produce things pretty aggressively
and resources don't go
to those who need it so it's
hypothetically in a socialist society
you would have all these resources just
um you would you would receive the means
of your labor
and you would have more you would have
more human rights it would be more
egalitarian and we wouldn't over produce
this magnitude because we wouldn't have
to
you don't need to so all of these bad
really bad things
that are happening are just consequences
of overproduction
and um improper resource a lot
maybe okay we're getting into the weeds
i want to do we should do an episode on
socialism
sometime i think that would be great i'm
down at any time anytime
and whenever you start your own channel
two and then i'll i'll hop on because i
feel like you need to elaborate on all
these things so much we'll do as many as
we can
because i wasn't i'm not ready like your
perspective on these
uh unpack that but let's see what else
do i have
i do want to talk about uh let's see
uh free speech in the paradox of
tolerance i get no actually i want to
talk about alienation
so a understand of aliens yes a nation
of aliens
let's go so marx using
post-modern marxist analysis uh marx
actually talks a lot about
the alienation that comes from modern
life and modern uh
factory work capitalist life
and it in consumerism as well so
and i'm going to wrap this around to
cancer culture and why i think this
happens
like what we were talking about with
jonathan heights work the other day i
think perhaps
yesterday i'm gonna i'm gonna wrap it
around so
he proposes that because you are no
longer able to actually actualize
like you cannot become actualized under
such oppressive working conditions and
such consumerism because you're just a
series of brands
and you don't have any life's fulfilling
work you just make someone else money
and due to the nature of working in an
office or whatever not seeing the end
means of your production
you don't actually like get the
fulfillment of meeting others or
feeling connected you become more
isolated with modern life we live in
boxes
we work in a small segment of the
production line
you don't feel close to your co-workers
that this
can hearken a need for really grasping
onto anything that gives you
individuality
and which can be really hyper specific
political views
so you get a young person out of college
that is really feeling this anxiety
deeply this i i'm not self-actualized
i'm having a crisis of meaning and i
realize that everything is fluid and i
need to hold on to something
i need to do i need to do something good
in the world i need i need to be
very specific so if you get really
specific
really hyper nuanced political opinions
you're now unique
and now you can go and force them and
you can feel better than others
so now you feel good i see how that
could be dangerous
i mean uh
yeah i think that's all really good
though i like that and i think that
that's why we get that
we get that uh you get that person out
of all this egalitarian inclusionary
thought
this the purity tester you know yeah
i just i just think of the
impossibilities that like i i'm just
thinking of standing
you know in a factory setting or a
lumber mill setting
with my hard hat on going what about
meaning and self-actualization
you know like what it would like it just
it's so far from what we're actually
doing like we've really it's we straight
off some sort
of path that we didn't realize that we
needed to kind of keep
pruned and and and trimmed like so um
i mean i guess this dips back a little
bit into into the the loss of god but
there does need to be some sort of
so so human beings need something that
we call meaning
we we it seems to be part of like so
maybe we should elaborate on that like
what like because is that something that
you think everybody agrees on is
i mean i know that we see it a lot
through you know a religious lens and
people reject that very quickly
but you know meaning and like feeling
that your life is
is fulfilled that you're you know living
up to your potential that you're
doing something to contribute to the
greater whole especially when you see
that the greater whole is [__] kind of
um like what what is that within us why
do we need why do we need that and how
do we
put it in doctor i feel like america is
in a really odd position for this
because we have the person i just talked
about and
people adjacent to it that are actually
aware of the collective and that we need
to like
they're they're aware of these things
but most of american culture
and capitalist belief is predicated on
stark and austere individuality
so like i am an individual and i am
indivisible and i am a part of nothing
but myself
and i seek to just do good by me
and i think that i'm not saying that
collectivism is better there's places
for all these things that's requires a
lot of nuance but
the american psyche is inundated with
not um
not looking outward at all not at all
and all the systems we have in place
propagate that too you gotta go like we
have got hype culture you got to go buy
the nicest stuff you got to be the
flashiest like look at me i need to go
buy a house in the suburbs
and then really isolate myself you just
are forced to live this
alienated life as this rugged individual
instead of focusing on hey we really
might need to come together
and um solve some problems and
figure this out right
yeah uh uh yeah it's interesting i feel
like you were pointing a little bit
about
a little bit towards uh kind of a lot of
stuff that i would call spiritual
like the thing within us that's that's
spiritual i mean
the the core teaching of of so much this
eastern philosophy that i study or
anything that like ram das or or alan
watts
would teach is selflessness you know
dualism and nondualism like the the
understanding that you are not
actually an individual as meant as much
as you want to like
we have a whole country based off of
individualism and
i i am this important thing uh
but the the core as we're kind of
missing this
uh forget the guy's name he writes the
the immortality key i think i had sent
you something from him the other day but
the the statement if you die before you
die
when you die you do not die or something
like that um
it's essentially like realizing that you
are not a person you are not
um and and you're not what you think you
are you are the universe the
consciousness
um the the the source the soul the god
the spirit the whatever
um continuing all everything
um because there's a way of living where
you can know
you can recognize this and um
uh know it it's an inner knowing but
also
be able to navigate in the world and
understand like okay like this is uh
these things are this is my ego acting
um so so we're basically we have
becometh
the ego in like in many ways in a couple
layers
and that is actually dangerous to the
future
of humanity if if one person
i mean we look at what we could blame
the ego for creating you know the
the nuclear bomb but now we realize like
oh
now we have this thing this this power
because of who we think we are we we
misconceive
reality and in the end that might take
away our reality
yeah well you could categorize just all
of american and western thought by just
like
actually just having an extremely stiff
and rigid view of
the self and the ego so i can even loop
this back to cancer culture definitely
because we can see both sides of this so
the one side that supposedly has gotten
this egalitarian or at least some people
in it have
come to these egalitarian conclusions
and it's collective and selfless and we
want everyone to like
be fulfilled in society somehow
due to the own ego trap has developed an
insular society that is has a purity
test to get in which is innately just
like us
that's like a sense of self thing is
like hey
in order to be with us you have to have
this hyper specific worldview and if you
don't believe exactly this we're not
going to let you in
which is the in opposition to all of the
ideas
that have been presented before them
which would just indicate you just have
such a strong potent sense of self and
you're so attached to this
you can't be fluent enough to accept
more people into it
and that's there's a lot of infighting
because of this and it takes something
that is really important that needs to
happen
which is just more people having more
liberty and makes it this
tiny little group because you have to
have you gotta you gotta
take the test and if you don't take it
you don't get in
and it's so frustrating so frustrating
for me
because i firmly believe that all these
ideas are
actually the best way to construct
society so to see people that i
align with be so wrong about so many
things
because of this is infuriating because
in the end people just
we just lose you just lose liberty like
the
collective thing that we have going on
all of like we have a collective shared
interest
in all this getting better and if these
people can't just let go of that
and figure it out and start trying to
make it better
instead of infighting it's going to be
really difficult and then on the other
end of the spectrum
i mean you just have just complete
like the self is real because it's just
how american society is
yeah i mean we're never really turned
we're never taught to
turn back on ourselves like it's not
even i mean i was i was what
26 before i even like ever really
truthfully thought about like what what
am i what it what is this like what does
it mean to be a conscious being like
those sorts of things and then
it's it's it's you know again it's
destabilizing but you know i think a lot
of people are pushed towards that way i
think a lot of people are
pushed towards spirituality push towards
trying to solve their mental health
issues or
their um you know things that they're
identifying with overly that are
creating their personal reality
creating their personality uh
and it's harming them like so it's like
you your your belief systems and the
things that you think that you are the
things you identify with
uh can start to harm you and you could
notice this and that's for me that's
like what
a spiritual awakening kind of started as
is this uh
this you know ending of like what the
[__] is going on like why is this
happening in my brain like why am i
thinking this way
blah blah you read a bunch of you start
reading a bunch of
you know books and podcasts and lectures
and all these things and you kind of
learn oh like
it was actually way behind me it was it
was actually it's one of these um
it's one of these things that have like
so learning that you're not
the thing that you identify with is like
looking into
uh you're inside a house and the lights
on behind you
and you're looking out the window and
suddenly you're able to like okay
i'm seeing nothing but the outside i'm
looking at my car outside
and you can shift your perspective to
notice the reflection behind you and
you're seeing your tv and your couch and
your living room
and the light behind you it's kind of
like that like
learning about this this uh this
truth that is the lack of self and lack
the lack of the individual
um that we are that is causing us to
fight against each other and causing us
to do in groups
our groups us them i'm this you are that
rather than we are
everything there is this slight
perception change that you can get
um besides putting lsd in the water
supply how do we get the uh
the basic consensus of people to kind of
realize the importance of
our own self-induced psychosis reality
we have here
uh do you want the comforting answer do
you want me to be true
um be true but then we'll have to offer
some sort of because
i don't want anybody who is like
depressed to be like completely
um i think the way that america exists
as is will not come to this realization
for a very long time mostly because of
some very powerful people spending a lot
of money to make it not so
like a lot of people spend a lot of
money to collectively
make sure that the working class of
people
don't antagonize against them really and
that's why i think that uh
like colleges have gotten a lot of flack
because the ideas that come out of
college
actually challenge that authority and
their ability to make money
to spend a lot of money not doing that
but the way that you do that is to push
a hyper individualistic
hard-nosed egoistic view of reality
of like black and white i am i am the
indivisible individual and this is the
way that i must be a reality and that is
deeply ingrained in american psyche and
i think it's going to be really hard
it's going to take a really long time
and a lot of real effort to get it our
way
and what is also hard is that the people
that have actually come to these
conclusions are falling for the trap on
the other end
of having that uh they're having like i
said uh the really hyper specific
worldview that you must conform to
rather than being inclusionary
as the actual ideas state you need to be
so but i mean it's hard because we've
got just such a big rift in ideology
that it's gonna be hard to come to a
like a middle ground conclusion where we
all work together
yeah i mean that's always been the
ultimate like
what humans really can do best is work
together you know
strong together people always growing
together
yeah so do you think it's vicarious do
you think that it's uh
uh um uh do you think that it's
malicious like do you think like because
often when we're talking about these
things i feel like what my mind wants to
do i don't think it's the correct way to
go i think it's kind of a waste of
thought but
what my mind does is i think about the
the evil people in the suits who they
know all this ego stuff they know
like how human interacts how human
psychology works
um and they're up there you know with
the strings i know there is some extent
of that but a lot of this dude i think
it's
nobody's staring the ship like i think
this is just the way we've always been
doing things has now started to like
cruise control itself and we're just
machinery we're
we're running it without the ability to
be like hold up like let's we have the
ability
we're the ones who created this thing we
don't have to like just keep on rolling
down the hill
we could stop the damn thing uh but do
you
but unless unless it's really like some
evil cabal
who's uh pulling all the strings and um
well the evil cabal is pulling all
strings is straight up just billionaires
it's just ceos
i mean because all the propaganda pushed
or all the money i mean if you go look
up the koch brothers they've spent
billions of dollars making sure that
america stays this hyper individualistic
austere society so they don't have to
give people more rights
more time off more money and because
what happens when people get more time
and more money is they self-actualize
because they don't need to work as much
you have time to ponder and then you
come to a lot of conclusions
that hey things are not how they ought
to be and then you destabilize how they
make money
and that i really think i mean that's
like really a baseline tenant of marxism
is just giving people this room to
self-actualize by not exploiting them
and i think that's why it's so scary for
the people that hold power
so until we can collectively figure out
that we're just all being exploited
and we need more time to self-actualize
it's going to be hard
because you need to self-actualize to
get there a little and
keep going keep going well i think a lot
of it falls on
the k to 12 education more than anything
is we're not taught epistemological
skills you're not taught about
metaphysics
you're not how to perceive reality in
new and interesting ways and come to
new conclusions which inherently makes
you really rigid
so you reject ideas that are not
absolutely insular to how you believe
and america tends to have a very black
and white view of reality
very objective there's no relativity
it's just
this is this and this is this there is
no bending in that you know i think i
think some of my riffs that come up or
my
my tips rather is we're
teaching young people i mean i don't
know how how you know
consecutive and how you know distributed
it really is but we are teaching people
now at the young age and those k
through 12 like all this gender study
stuff or all you know things in that
realm
and it's not true is that not is that
not true that's just what i've heard
no no people are just so a lot of these
people i actually looked into this
that's really not taught in schools at
all like the only thing that would be
touched on now
because like trans activism is real is
that gender is a social construct which
it is and i can
prove to you after this but no it's like
kind of a niche college thing
but the people that don't want this
destabilization
will rail and lament against it because
it just is like
it causes you to make less money it's
just this whole thing um
more it's more of the the looky looky
looky looky let's let's argue about
gender and let's go let's talk about
this it's like why aren't we let's
let's talk about the things that are
important let's let's teach people at a
young age
how to think what it means uh what
holism means
how to take care of your bodies because
we have like what over half of america
60 something percent of america is like
super obese and unhealthy
somebody makes a lot of money on making
that happen
no do you think that it's conscious do
you think like if i went to the
the ceo of like the person making the
calls i mean there's such a big
organization at this point there's
probably hundreds if not thousands but i
went to like
the the head honcho the the creme de la
creme the the main guy
of of coke and i'm like hey man give me
10 minutes and i'll tell you how you're
ruining
everybody and you're going to kill the
whole world like is is do you think he's
even like
ever thought about that do you think
he's actually like evil do you think
he's just
doing the thing where he was trained to
go to to college after school and he's
following the things and he does his job
and he's like well hey i'm
i'm within the law like his brain may
not even be able to think on the level
of
humans being one species but more rather
he's just such an individual he's such a
rigorous
ego that he has inability to see what
the [__] going on and what he's doing
um i firmly believe that is absolutely
malicious and i don't think they were
born like that
i think the system that we have in place
uh
really just encourages people to be like
that because what is the
number one and only goal of the
corporation
you make money you make money that's it
that's all you do that's literally there
is no political agenda
really it's just we need to keep society
as is
stable so we need to keep a really
narrow world view
nice and stable and then we need to make
money because what
cigarettes lobbied to doctors uh the
sugar industry paid
like 50k in the 60s to uh discredit fad
as being the problem
like companies over and over and over
have shown that they have so many
examples of this
and i actually really want to talk about
this because this gets railed on it's
like
all these liberal corporations they're
doing won't cancel culture look
they say trans people exist which
it's like like people will just get so
upset about corporations being
these liberal hellholes quote unquote
but let's look at this let me
let's let's present this i don't know
how to do this on soon but i'm going to
try because here's some examples to show
you that there is just um
will you let me screen share um
you can share all participants yeah cool
i think that should be able to do
okay yeah like bottom line
they will just pick whatever
okay so sure
i'll present this can you see this oh
yeah all right
so let's take a look at this so people
got mad about corporations hanging the
pride flag and all their logos look what
they did in the middle east where it's
uh
really really not socially acceptable to
be gay
no this is a actually a definitive
this is actually a definitive virtue
signal
yeah some people are like hey
these corporations are doing all this
canceling look how liberal they are
look at that they need to make money and
most people
like 65 percent of people have
left-leaning views in america
statistically
so you're appealing to majority this is
on the front edge of society
coca-cola and ford both worked
rigorously with the nazis more than
anyone else
more than any other company they sold
fanta to nazi germany
okay and then look at this one
hey i think coke casually dropped a
singular and
uh a singular they into that ad uh
denoting that they're using they
instead of he or she to be inclusionary
yes glad you noticed
parker we value and celebrate diversity
and then the same week
coca-cola accused of funding colombian
death squads
okay it seems like a [__]
movie plot so do you think that they
care about anything but profit
not literally nothing and that's just
the way society is constructed
okay but how do we see this as a like
this is a problem problem like we can't
continue to do this i know this is the
way things are
and it's like well hey that's capitalism
man like
i mean dude what's the answer
so if you i'm gonna say that's what
we're supposed to be figuring out like
i think that a lot of smart people did
figure it out and if you go look at any
like modern socialist thinkers like
they're down for egalitarianism they
also
are like highly ecologically concerned
so
it constructs society in a more stable
way that is concerned about
um not not lighting it on fire and
obviously these people
shouldn't have the keys they don't care
about anything but profit they and
oh that's uh another slide that i would
like to show but
they don't care about anything for
profit that's their only goal they have
stakeholders
so they will in its short term they will
literally
let the world burn just to make extra
money next year
and they do it the ocean is on fire this
week
so to say that corporations are these
like liberal paradises and these
absolute insular messes
is i think kind of silly
you know we're being pointed where again
we're being told what to what to pay
attention to and
we're missing out on another important
thing all effort is just to insulate
profit
that's it all of it they don't believe
in anything they don't care about
anything
it's just did we make more money than
last quarter
besides us pointing out like okay
coca-cola is evil they suck
down with coca-cola like what is the one
higher
meta step behind this like why is this a
problem
because i think that we get caught up
with like hey here's the bad guys and i
think a lot of people might be thinking
like cool
let's just you know let's just cancel
coca-cola let's just
let's just boycott coca-cola let's just
what like what's the what's the bigger
problem here and how could it be like
reeled back into
you know the average well i actually
just wanted to show this
to show that corporations are apolitical
and that it's not
any one corporation needs to be
demonized the structure that allows
corporations to exist in this space must
be altered
right there yeah exactly that sentence
right there is very personal
i'm not mad at any one corporation i
mean i'm mad at all of them but
fundamentally we construct the society
where the win condition is make more
money
so we need to remake the win condition
which is maximize human
like prosperity
not make more money because we have
starving people in america
the richest nation that's ever existed
and this happens
so if we can't reconstruct society to
where the goblins don't have all the
gold and just make more gold
how is anyone gonna ever be actualized
how is everyone gonna live a good life
because it's just rank exploitation and
this happens this is what actual virtue
signaling is
this is the real clinical definition of
a virtue signal
do you think do you think that there's a
way they programmed a bot
in an algorithm to virtue signal that
hard like it's like at this point they
know social psychology
so well like they definitely have their
hands in the pockets of whatever
science they need to be able to get a
hold of whatever data they need to have
to to form some sort of algorithm that
would like
directly you know uh i don't know
into what what society cares about the
most right now and they
they literally have infinitesimal
amounts of money like
unfathomable amounts of capital and they
can have people know all this stuff they
got pr
teams just to keep up on it
like this is so calculated and then uh
just because it's on the next slide i do
uh
i do want to talk about this because we
run into some interesting conflicts
people talk about tolerance and free
speech
this is the paradox of tolerance so in
order to be
to remain tolerant and to remain a
tolerant society you must be intolerant
to
intolerance which is
i you people i see people say the left
is intolerant
but they're just being intolerant to
intolerance a lot of times
and that comes down to a lot of
unconscious buying and social
conditioning
on people that may have uninspected some
things
so if you see okay so i guess we'll go
over conscious bias as well
let's see if i don't mess this up i've
heard this recently all right
so a young woman is going into surgery
um she leaves her her dad is at work
at home and uh she uh
wakes up from surgery and says
and here's a voice like
uh daughter
it's like well what did what did the
surgeon look like to you
because if you imaged a man
it couldn't be your dad was at home the
mother is a surgeon but the unconscious
bias there would be
you associate surgeons with being men so
you pictured a man even though in this
story you already were totally aware
that her father was at home so it's like
sometimes the conclusions that we just
come to
we didn't consciously choose but they
actually have some interesting bias and
ramifications
and need to be in inspected yeah yeah so
those are also things that are so
subtle that they're not always profound
realizations they're like
very you could really notice and skip
right back oh you can keep plowing
through sometimes with this it's just
the smallest speed bump you kind of
notice
this even got me a very very very
very inclusionary person i i got hit by
this one too i imaged a man
which is just this is how deeply
ingrained a lot of it is and when
some people are when you're being
intolerant to intolerance
and the intolerance you're being
intolerant to doesn't understand that
it's being intolerant it's going to
cause a lot of issues
because it's just like what do you mean
how like you're the one being intolerant
and
we get into this like pissy infighting
and like who gets silenced whose opinion
doesn't get to get hurt
who gets cancelled you know it's and i
would think that whoever's
person who backs down unfortunately yeah
it's like whose idea
um i guess we just need to come to
fundamental principles about what we
want society to be and we can't conclude
them
because there's just a like a lot of ape
machine
machinery like unconscious bias and a
lot of this uninspected world view
that is really just smashing together
yeah i mean i think that it's being
greatly accelerated i think that
we need to look at um you know not just
internet not just technology but really
phones and like how much that really has
you know our not just social media but
really really phones like we are
all of this was going to be a problem
regardless like it's just something that
would have eventually happened
with this thing that we've created here
uh but
it's it has been like really rapidly
excelled and now you know
here we are noticing that you know again
seeing the writing on the walls that
we can't continue to go this way what
i'm what i'm proposing spencer is like
how do i think within the next five
years we're going to have to address
this not just contemplate it not just
like like i i get that we're just you
know random dudes and this is not a big
giant podcast or anything but
like the they're they're we need to
change our narrative
about what we're talking about in our
pop culture because our pop culture is
how
of uh changes and effects and things are
pushed
or ushered anyway yeah so i will
actually i'm gonna interject a little
bit so
it's funny because um ideas of modernity
set narratives like um i mean any idea
i'll just we're talking about marxism
marxism narratives is the owner and
ruler classes fight with the working
class right it's a power struggle that's
the narrative that is set up
um but post-modernism sets meta
narratives
so it analyzes a bunch of ideas and
tries to conjoin one single narrative to
come to new conclusions
but and i think that we got to get on
the same page like you said in a lot of
ways
the problem is we're having at least in
political philosophy we're having a
really interesting rift because
it it's really akin to
america i think america is really
susceptible to this but
like pre-world war ii italy like you
have a
you have one set of uh beliefs that are
like
incredibly left-leaning they're very
egalitarian we want to
bolster the working class unionize we
want to strip the owners of society from
their wealth and distribute it
right this would be the socialist
communist whatever you want to call it
the left-leaning ideology and then we
have the
right side so it's um categorized by
like hyper-nationalism uh stark
individuality
and um just like like a massive in group
and that we like we are the we're the
greatest as a nation
and we must come together and be very
strong as individuals
and uh any out group of this needs to be
ostracized and we must be really potent
and these ideas don't work well together
they're polar opposites
so as the friction so this is in marx's
theory as well so
capitalism is inherently unstable and it
will eventually fail
to get to the latest stages where we're
having we're having total systemic
failure which we are now
so we have all our all our institutions
are corrupt
um politicians aren't doing any of their
work people are being exploited it's
hard to live and it's causing a lot
of friction and there's two ways it can
go
it can go to the socialist way where we
decide that we need to separate all of
this money
and push it all to the working class
unionize and
build up a more egalitarian society or
it can turn into fascism
which is that hyper-nationalistic like
it italy
in 1942 and many
philosophers political philosophers have
thought this was the case
fat both fascists and socialist
philosophers have thought this would
happen
and i think let me look at the divide in
america right now
like look at look at the hyper spectrum
of response to
the systemic failing of like actually
identitative liberal values which is
something more than being liberal in
america i don't really want to go into
it
but like so now we have a huge
problem there's a big rift and like
people have thought about this forever
people knew this was gonna happen
and what happens on the other side of it
is just
i don't know i don't know where i'm
going with this but yeah
dude i yeah again i think we get to this
point where we just need
we need some you know mother we need
some alpha you know
uh you know i mean that in a female way
too like
so we need somebody to stand up and go
like i'm just envisioning this
a bunch of [__] drunk vikings in a in
a mess hall
just arguing and yelling and they're
they're arguing and yelling and
discussing real problems but it's
escalating right now [__] you
and you're this and everybody's just
yelling and then we're having a food
fight blah blah we need somebody to
stand up and just like
hey stop yes there's problems let's sit
down and actually solve them
what we're doing the way we're speaking
to one another the things that we're
doing right now
is unhelpful stop like stop being such
monkey minds and let's actually use like
this
very powerful you know tool that we have
yeah and i
so i dabbled in pretty extreme
perspectives of political opinion just
to like
just to test them out and um i've come
kind of full circle to more of a
meta-analysis of this i actually
just whatever will achieve the
principles that i
wish to happen in society i don't care
what you really call it
but society has to work for everyone and
if it doesn't work for one group it's
going to be really bad
so we can't really agree on the problems
because there's a lot of like
propaganda and just public agitation
about
so on one hand you have
the news who says some news sites say
hey you're feeling agitation it's hard
to get work you're underpaid
um it's not because this is like just a
system that just is built like this
and you're being exploited by your by
the ceo is making billions of dollars
it's actually mexicans
it's actually people coming across the
border they're taking your jobs
so now we've found there's a pain point
and we have two
really different solutions and
somebody's paid a lot of money to make
it that way
so it's what are you doing yeah how do
you how do you deconstruct that because
you just are
blasted you're blasted with propaganda
yeah it's exactly like we're busy
fighting about the dumb things and we're
fighting about them in dumb ways
and there has to be some sort of snap
out of it situation that's what i'm
thinking like i don't know
i mean i don't know what that could
possibly mean or do maybe that's what
this whole alien thing ploy is maybe it
is going to be
what is it project bluebeam or whatever
they were talking about where they're
gonna project
some aliens and it's gonna give us an
excuse to come together as a human
species
and fight the bad aliens and then we'll
be like oh yeah we did need some sort of
war event
to make us realize what's truly
important and how to come together and
that we have a future if we just plan on
it
yeah this uh really got routed in the
political discussion and i want to
apologize
but it's just like the nature of this
first off
but i don't actually know if that was
apologize for that i appreciate your
perspective
on you know you bring politics into it
and it's something that i don't dabble
into as much so i think that
my like messy creative side uh or you
know
perception of these same things creates
a fun uh yeah i don't
i don't like to do it from the average
like um
this is my stance believe it i would
rather do it from a power dynamic in
philosophy stance because i actually
think that's how we come to conclusions
but
on the sake of the alien thing i think
that we would come together and get
right back to fighting i think that
until we can figure out
the um ape strong together that we will
always go back to resorting to that
because we just have so much stuff so
much like all the social constructs
that have just been put in place over a
millennia
have just remained like race um
just just stuff like that that is really
not
real but we put a lot of thought into
and it's divisive
it's a reason to other people and that's
just like innate to our biology
until we can get enough friction in
society to realize that this doesn't
serve us
i don't think it's gonna go away but i
do think that friction is coming
and i think that maybe some of the stuff
that's coming out of universities is
kind of pushing on the boundaries of
what society could probably
deal with right now when it comes to
fluidity but
i do think the demolition of a lot of
social constructs for a more
fluid society will be helpful in the
long run because then we have less stuff
to differentiate each other on
you have less others if everything's
fluid
[Music]
so i think i think canceled culture can
just be considered
more of god more of gossip like it's
it cancel culture it can be more gossip
than like it's not actual problem solved
we think it's problem solving
we think that we're actually finding the
boogie man like you had stated before
we're finding the boogeyman and we're
all right there he is let's [__] lock
him up
but it's it's a distraction it is gossip
i literally think of i go i have a
small amount of of our friends on
snapchat
um i go on there and obviously like as
soon as i see the story page
you start seeing these tabloids and i
will i'm addicted to my damn phone and
all the pretty colors so i scroll
and i'll look for for uh you know a few
seconds and there's always like
you'll never believe what so and so did
you'll never believe what kanye west
said
so and so leaked and it's gossip it's
tabloids it's uh
it's a like we want to know what's going
on i think we need to like
as individuals as just consumers of all
of this
cool exciting fun flashy phone exciting
you know
made like a slot machine this cool thing
is
distracting us and making us dummies
it's making us care about dummy stuff
like we why do we give a flying f about
what so-and-so is doing what so-and-so
is saying
i get that not everybody's going to have
the interest of like hey we've got real
problems and we need to solve it but
there does need to be more people more
of the general public focusing on
things of importance because it'll
change what they think about what they
talk about what they do what they study
uh what they spend their time doing and
in turn that creates more people who are
able to
cognitively actually solve these
problems in our near future
yeah and i agree i think it's hard
because
i can't expect anyone to spend all their
time ruthlessly analyzing their thoughts
because it's super exhausting and i know
a bunch of people that just would never
enjoy that
that's fine it's just what i enjoy and i
can't really expect all of people to do
it but i
would really like it if more people
stopped feeding into it and just like
cared how their neighbors were doing
at the end of the day you know like hey
we're like all suffering and it's pretty
obvious and we're really focusing on
this one thing but like
what are our commonalities how do we all
suffer under the system why are we
focusing on these
big hot button jake paul is getting
cancelled and now everyone there's just
so much human attention
put into something that's so [__]
frivolous
like when like your co-workers are
getting exploited because you don't talk
about wages together but you're worried
about jake paul
yeah for real like hey is it because
it's easier it's
because it's served to us in a dish it's
because it's like this instant dopamine
hit it's this instant like
hey you you feel good and this feels
like a distraction this feels like i
mean this is like an addictive behavior
this is like
i really want to you know take care of
all these things on the weekend but
instead i'm going to drink because
that's what i always do every weekend
you know it's these sort of things
i'm saying that from my personal
experience like we we we become these
sack of habits and especially it's this
instant
sag habits like snapchat and uh not
snapchat social media our the corporate
press our news media
um our technology is really giving
all these mother efforts access to our
beat holes
and they're just tunneling through the
the magic of technology and putting
their
hands up our butts and moving our mouths
for us and telling us what to talk about
and what to do and what to think and who
to argue with and who's the enemy and
who's good and who's bad
and all these things but we need to i
think just
watch out watch out and be aware and
control
and uh again i'll use the word just
aware i think it's the best be aware of
how our technology
is changing us and changing our
discourse towards things that are
unimportant and we need to
more so allow like our actual
intelligence our actual
you know intuitive feeling and following
things like hey this doesn't feel right
but we can't have access to that because
we're constantly distracted by what
they're telling us to fight about what
they're telling us to argue about what
they're telling us is important they're
saying hey here's your identity
it's being threatened so it's actually
destabilizing
and that's a real thing but we need to
go from there recognize that and say
okay now i i understand that my identity
is being threatened but what is my
identity what does it really mean how
does it equate to a difference in the
person across from me
how is this actually helpful to the
betterment in the future of our
children and grandchildren and the great
grandchildren after that yeah well i
think the first step
is actually caring about others
you know you got to actually care about
others you know
you have to think about more than your
myopic worldview
that in your own self-actualization to
what you think reality is
you need to come to terms the fact that
the way you perceive reality and your
baseline existence is just
not how others are and in fact others
might suffer
and until you can step out of this
insular
always internal position and look at the
world around you and realize things are
not how they ought to be it's gonna be
very hard to come to that conclusion
i can i want to interject where you're
going i'm sorry i i was just thinking i
think this is a good
good important thing uh a good practice
for this a good like
uh way for an average person to actually
do
do this and by this i mean um care for
one another like how could you
truthfully care for other people
more like maybe people listening to this
are nihilistic and they [__] hate
people and they just want to hang out
themselves and they
think people suck and it's hard to care
about anybody about themselves because
maybe that's how they were taught since
they were a young person
maybe they were taught to just look out
for themselves um or maybe they just
don't really have them really thought
about it like it's not that they hate
other people
but they just don't it's like i'm doing
my thing and i literally have no time to
concentrate on what other people are
doing these are the people yeah that's
what's going on
these are the people that i saw like a
couple weeks ago i saw this guy i was
driving down the road
and uh he rolls down his truck window
and he takes a big old lot of taco bell
garbage and just throws it out on the
freeway and i i think it's not that he's
being
he's unconscious he doesn't realize like
the the bigger
effects that he's having on things so
what i would like to do
for people for people who are listening
i think a good practice
is uh what would be called meta loving
kindness meditation
i'm not saying you have to actually do
this meditation but it is something
try to insert a thought like this that
i'm about to explain
into your daily life it's almost
something that prayer can even access
with a lot of people
so whatever your version of prayer or
mantra or meditation
add this into it try to bring it into
your thought system
once a day basically uh it's difficult
to
bring in things like self-love right
away like you're sitting on the cushion
and it's like all right
think about yourself and how much do you
love yourself but it's so hard to have
access to so what they do
in meta loving kindness meditation is
you
um you sit and you become present and
you do take the beginning time to
concentrate on your breath you become um
here
and now you kind of get in tune with
your five senses
you kind of slow down your thought
process you increase your concentration
and then what you do
is you think about um just someone that
you have an uncomplicated relationship
with that
you love like one of one of your friends
one of your friends back home
one of your childhood friends one of
your current friends maybe it's maybe
it's your dog and just
kind of just think about them and think
about them try to visualize them in your
mind
think about them being happy think about
them being um
you know successful like like truthfully
really think about
like one of your very good friends and
just
think about okay if i could i would give
them everything they
they ever wanted like if i was somehow
in control of
their like financial and you know
uh future happiness i would give that to
them
and you'll you'll notice you're sitting
here and you just continue kind of
thinking
visualizing this person and wishing them
well you're wishing them success
and then you can kind of think about
them as like man they were
of course i want them to do well like
they were i know their childhood
experiences
i know that they were one one times six
years old and then they were seven years
old and then they were eight and they
were a whole person they were born they
have a family they have a mother they
have a father
all these things so you can essentially
with meta meditation
um eventually you can get to a point
where you kind of get you're able to
think about yourself
in in this way and it brings this very
nice ease this soft
um hereness to your being
but with practice of thinking about
people that you certainly
do love and you really think about them
on a holistic time when you think about
them
on a they were a child once and they've
had they had to get a driver's license
and take a driver's permit and they have
they wake up every morning
and all my neuroses and all the things
that i think about they have their own
version of them they have their own
struggles and they have their own
desires and all these things
uh it really creates this softness in
you and you not only appreciate the
people that you do love and the people
that you are bringing to mind your
family members and your friends and your
loved ones
but you're also able to now project that
onto strangers you can really look at
your neighbor like you were saying we
need to love our neighbors more you look
at your neighbor and you're like
yeah oh he's just he has his own
experiences he had his own childhood he
had his own upbringing like
he is who he is because of the things
that have happened
and you can find appreciation we're not
meeting them because
with this study of or this practice of
meta-loving kindness you can kind of
more
meet people uh on where you see them
uh truly rather than where you disagree
with them like whether you see them as a
being and you see them as a whole
long term they're going to die one day
and their parents are going to pass away
one day if they haven't already like
they're going to
deal with extreme suffering of some
level
you can really bring in a
it pushes away this hey your neighbor is
actually a
this what the news tells you our social
media our technology tells us your
neighbor is this
you miss that they're also the same
thing you are they're love
they're a family member they're a son
they're their child they're a father
they're
you miss out on all these things so
anyway that's my quick side step on meta
loving kindness meditation
you can practice it on your friends and
it actually increases your ability to
love other people in the world
yeah i will actually give you a school
of thought or a systemic way to think
that well you might arrive at the same
conclusion if uh
you don't wish to do that or do both so
if i can propose that free will is not
completely free and you don't always um
choose all your uh outcomes and actions
you didn't necessarily pick
the uh operating system that you've uh
been operating under for your whole life
so
if you just are a collection of thoughts
and ideas that have kind of been handed
to you
if you can see that in other people you
can look at their surroundings and
realize how they came to these
conclusions
and and they didn't necessarily choose
any of them probably actively
and logically it can make a lot of sense
why they did because this is the
exposure they had and it's not
necessarily a slight on them it's more
of a systemic problem
so we have these things in place that
have shown these people these things and
images and these are the conclusions
that they didn't arrive at on their own
and instead of being angry at this
person
for concluding these things and which
they were given you can look at the
system as a whole and figure out
hey where do we mess up
what is what is the influence
yeah we are we're so again i feel like
yeah you pointed the same thing
we're distracted by the incorrect things
like it's it's not that one thing is
more true than the other maybe there is
truth in all of it maybe
maybe your neighbor is this or that but
it's not the only thing about them and
it's not the first place to meet them
because that's not how you solve
problems you're just going to
argue or gossip or waste time if you
meet them on
where they lack or what they're doing
correctly yeah i guess i'm getting it
i'm sorry for the interruption but as
just as a
a lot of the ideas that i presented
earlier predicate on thinking
systemically rather than that
about the individual so you can look
thing from a sociological
curious standpoint so if you look at the
total human thought that's going on in a
certain system or society you can
pinpoint where these things are coming
from
and rather than being upset of one
person for believing this you can
analyze the system
and then you actually become a lot more
empathetic to these people because they
didn't necessarily choose this
you were just like a reacting to these
things you are being nurtured
into believing this so usually
trying to change the frame of reference
in which they would think about these
things is going to be way more helpful
than just being mad at them for
believing them as ridiculous as it is
because it's really unhelpful
to be extremely mad at somebody for
believing something that you find to be
heinous maybe even
because the system that generated them
still stands
so right right dude i think actually
what you just said i i
it's actually really cool that we just
stumbled into systems thinking while
talking about cancer culture because i
think that's actually a great
that's a great like uh like uh rope rope
down the hole
you know because i think that there is
something profound
you and i are systems thinkers but there
is something profound that happens
people who are not systems thinkers they
never really realized it was an option
or thought about it
um like it could really change
a lot of the of your way of thinking
like if you learn about systems thinking
there was some youtube um
i think honestly if you probably even
just type in like what is systems
thinking and you watch a couple of those
older lectures
there's some great stuff on there man so
what is just to overly
drill in the hole on systems thinking
what is systems thinking and how does it
help us
uh better solve problems
okay so systems thinking is a
meta-analysis of
the uh social constructs what's meta
uh i use it in a different way a
holistic overview
from varied points of view of analyzing
something
to come to a greater conclusion so like
there are systems in place
and they have outcomes this is like
sociology touches on this like just
sociological data so i mean i guess i
can look at any systemic problem
so if you have a group of people that
are constantly having the same outcome
under the same circumstances with no
intervention
it's more than likely a systems problem
and you're not actually going to be able
to solve it without a systemic solution
so and that is way different than the
you did bad you need to do better as an
individual because that doesn't really
solve any problems
it doesn't so many problems if you can't
alter the system to
change the outcomes you're not going to
make large changes so thinking about
systems as a whole is the only way to
actually elicit any real change
so this is this is immediately makes me
think that we need to grab pitchforks
and go to the street though so what do
we really do like
is this just a like well you know that's
politics though and what you got to do
if you really want to make some changes
you got to go down to your local
governing
system and you know and i'm not trying
to mock that
and i think that's a good that's a great
thing but uh it does seem like
i i don't know that this problem can be
solved by mere politics alone at this
point
um i think it can i really do think it
can but it needs to actually have a
concerted
top bottom down effort how do we how do
we put a
shaman into the room of politicians
then then we could we could do this
right how do we how do we
hire a monk to be a part of our law
making system and he has to be a vital
we have a round table of people like
that don't require power
they don't seek it out and they never
will
that's why this has to be a grassroots
ground up thing and
i think it is semi-problematic that's
why i think the individualistic solution
to political problems is troubling
because if i can
just tell you you need to pick yourself
up by your bootstraps
all your problems are your fault there
are no other factors you didn't succeed
in this perfect meritocracy
because you did bad there are no other
factors
that's problematic when i can go look at
you can predict
somebody's living where they live by
looking at their great great grandparent
zip code and
statistically it's likely for them to
still live there
so if you tell me that systems thinking
and system solutions aren't actually the
thing
i don't know what would be because
obviously if a meritocracy was real
people would move a lot more there'd be
way more mobility
so this i need to pull myself off my
bootstraps method it doesn't actually
work at all
it doesn't get anything done nobody you
can't do it actually the funny thing
is that's an old soviet joke because you
literally can't pull yourself up by your
bootstraps
that's doesn't mean possible i know it's
actually a spiritual point or two if you
really think about it like
uh yeah yeah so
so figuring out the systemic change that
needs to happen
on a large scale getting everyone
together
and then pushing the people in power to
do it because at the end of the day who
really holds power
it's people we hold power we just have
been isolated we've been alienated as
marx would say
from understanding our true potency and
our hyper individuals
individualistic society has uh only
propagated that
rather than because we think that ape
strong alone but ape is strong together
but we can't conclude this because half
of us think
are like bootstraps not in systems
right right yeah so i think it is so do
you think that the average like the
average listener
let's say do you think it like what what
can we point out then like um
it's important to think system system
well you just need to have an increase
well you don't need to
but it certainly would help in analyzing
the world and people other people's pain
points
especially protected class of people
that just have an innate sense of
sociological curiosity
so a lot of times you
like so let's see any any predicted
class
let's see african americans so they've
got worse outcomes than other races in
america
do you think that's because every
african-american just didn't bootstrap
it
or is it because maybe a system that is
in place disadvantages this group of
people more than others
it's thinking like that so like and
that's actually like critical race
theory actually is that
that's it it's just systems thinkings uh
like pressed upon race
and usually thinkers who are into hyper
individualism really don't like it
right yeah did you go over did you go
over critical race theory that's it
that's all it is really
it's just trying to look at um
i mean critical theory in general is
this but using a sociological lens
to look at um problems in society and
impressing systemic changes to get
better outcomes
rather than you need to do better
yeah so yeah i guess systems thinking is
going to point out because we do need to
it's just another case of yes but you
need to look broadly
as big as possible yeah and that's what
we
so how do we have a
how do we get an entire species on a
planet to
continue backing out of their [__]
and really go meta how do we
how do we all have an agreement of
being the eagle being able to take a
glance like we don't have to all remain
there the whole time
but there does need to be some sort of
boom like hey oh yeah we're all one
and that is important because this
yeah i don't know i'm always asking the
impossible no answer
questions i understand that i'm a total
ironically after what i just told you
um you be individually thinking about
things like this
so more individualism yeah because it's
not necessarily bad it's actually good
in a self-help context it's just bad in
a political sense
so if if slowly over time you can get
more and more people
to adopt a way of thought that actually
leads to better outcomes you'll receive
those outcomes
and i think conversations like this are
how it happens slowly over time
and people are waking up to it i mean
like sixty percent of young people
like really question the uh hard-nosed
austere way
that like american politics and american
thought is gone and it's because of
suffering
because people have been suffering like
there is there is a call
and it is being answered it's just it's
gonna take a while and i
firmly and i know i've been pretty
nihilistic for this whole talk
but i really believe this over all of
history
more people have had more rights and
more liberty over time forever
it's always gotten better it's always
gotten better
and although sometimes we have dips in
this it just continues because people
that fight for this don't
just stop they don't stop a gay marriage
they don't just stop at workers rights
they don't stop at the eight hour work
week
this just always gets better okay but
okay i i was just thinking uh kind of
back to the coca-cola thing like
you have more than more rights than ever
but like your brain is like your brain
chemicals are being
uh scientifically studied and then used
against you like
you have every right to drink as much
coca-cola as you possibly
could want forever but then there's also
this other thing
of but you know you're you're gonna die
but we're gonna get you so addicted to
it
that you know or it's gonna make you
sick in these ways or it's gonna like
there there is this god it's it's so
hard because you want to like
you start choosing freedoms but it seems
like we're almost
unable to like i see how frust like i
i'll literally sit down in front of some
food and like okay i'm only gonna eat
this amount of it and then sure enough
i'll eat the whole thing and then
whatever
i'll eat something else afterwards like
the the self-control
i have every right to eat all these
things but i do also see
how it's harming me and i don't seem to
be able to stop you know it's like we're
all
addicts of all these different things
and i'm sure other people have this like
with diet coke or mcdonald's or whatever
it's like you have every right and you
should have every right to drink as much
diet coke as you want
but also like it's it's killing people
yeah i guess it's not exactly what i was
referencing when it comes to freedom i
more so just mean like
you don't have to work 40 hours a week
like we don't need to be that productive
but
on that end yeah i think that that needs
to be tempered with
um education i think that actually
fundamentally all this is an education
problem and the people that pay for
education i mean
literally all the problems we have i
think are fundamentally education
problem
because they uh turn out a populist that
is
not introspective they don't know about
epistemology
they don't know how to critically think
or analyze uh the world around them in
any way but the myopic ones that they've
been taught to
so if because if you go look at um just
in
metadata or like any health surveys so
the higher a level of someone's
education is the more likely they are to
eat well
that's it yeah so this is and i don't
think that that is just because these
people are special
i think they've just been exposed to
enough thought to come to these
conclusions
right and we just need to expose young
people to that but the problem is
people a lot of money spend a lot of
money to make sure that that doesn't
happen
yeah we're god dude we're we're
seriously taught
what to think not how to think in so
many ways well and by design
too by design it's not like an accident
because if you have people that think if
you have a populist of things really
critically they question a lot of all
the [__] that goes on
and if you question [__] that
destabilizes
authority and authority has one goal
maintain power
right that's it one goal maintain power
so our power dynamics of how we socially
um
construct our existence as human beings
on planet earth
is going to have its own self-destruct
feature that's just on a time it's just
a time bomb is really that's all
yeah i guess we'll know we'll know the
solutions uh as they come about
so okay so in the meantime you know
looping back to cancer culture and what
can everybody as individuals do
um work on your damn self and and look
at these things
look at these things don't take them so
face value like don't
just listen to what the corporate press
and to what all these you know phone
apps and stuff are telling you or what
uh what the popular video that day is
like
because that's gonna make you feel
righteous and make you feel like yeah i
believe that too i'm on the right side
but
it's not exactly like just question it
just
question a little bit more like who who
put that there how is that full circle
why are we arguing about this what are
things that could be possibly more
important
um what else do you have spencer if we
want to uh start rounding the the curve
of the end of this podcast here
um i think that i would just i'm going
to say a fair warning to
people engaging in just um
youtube rabbit hole or listening to
others speak um
just be wary of uh language that you
don't know
the definition to that's actually why i
defined all those terms previously
because
they're extremely misused and sometimes
maliciously
so a really common tactic for people
with any political leaning
to graft their ideology onto you is to
take the words from whatever the
opposition is
use them improperly and all intermingled
and then
speak in vague enough terms for you to
be able to graft your idea onto it
so now they convince you to not like a
bunch of stuff that you don't know about
and speak vaguely enough without
defining terms to then
in turn just agree with them so it's
tricky scaffolding from an elusive smart
person
yeah and it's just how
people are able to slowly inundate you
with
their personal ideology and it may not
be malicious and it may be malicious but
this is just a thing that happens so
just be wary of someone
if you can deconstruct somebody's
sentence and you realize they didn't
really say anything
didn't say anything they choose a bunch
of buzzwords and they're speaking in
like
a lot of really loose metaphorical terms
that don't ever hard answer
answer or heart knows answer questions
uh i would
not say to devalue them but definitely
introspect and go figure out what
they're talking about
what are these things that they're
criticizing what does the opposition
think and where do i fit in
don't just go look at it to confirm what
you already believe don't really look at
it go really look at what this
whatever is being criticized because
then you can at least
round out your view because you either
come to terms of the fact that you don't
like it
and he's right or he or she is right or
hey maybe there's some nuance to this
and now
you have a multi-perspective viewpoint
of something that was pretty myopic in
the first place
due to whatever you're listening to i
have another door that i just opened up
thinking about this uh
do you think there's any issues here
with how our
information ecology is combined with our
entertainment structure yes
100 yes it's mostly just because of the
nature of the internet
so if you can be as broadly appealing as
possible
and use that really flowery beautiful
language and trick people into thinking
that you're like a root like
an intelligent person not just like a
pseudo intellect
you can really collect a lot of people
and then that hits people like it when
you use really fluttery language they
don't like to get into the weeds
they just like want you to sound smart
and agree with them
a lot of i feel like i speak
rather inconcisely i'm a very like
sloppy
uh uh um like
i don't know i feel like i almost fall
into this category of like don't don't
listen to people like me because i'm
kind of just
but we also i mean we also one
don't claim to be two don't hold any
power and
three just want to do good stuff
you know like intense it's just
different when you like are a monolithic
intelligent person in society and then
you still do this
right you know like i feel like it's
pretty obvious that i'm just like a guy
just figuring it out and i have no
malicious intent i just want society to
be better
but smarter devils than i have whipped
up more loose language
to fool a lot of people and garner a
really big following and then take money
from them
really most people are trying to sell
books
you know but i feel like that's the i
would wear that on a shirt
most people are trying to sell books
that's real though that's that is real
um
look okay this is a tangible like look
at self-help it's like the same six
ideas just
recycled between like some just barely
different framing
and whoever can just like get the hit
get enough popularity to make the book
with the six ideas wins
they just keep going yeah i mean it is
all kind of pointing at the same thing
but as someone who has been
interested and fairly enveloped and
self-help since i was like 16
like i've always it is
dude it's very interesting to me because
so for it is pointing to a lot of the
same ideas
but how we get there how we understand
what the person's talking about
very much has has to do with our own
upbringing like for me
i feel like i wasn't taught very much by
adults like i kind of had to teach
myself everything i just had a
an upbringing that put me as a solo
independent person fairly early
and so for me when i was able to
discover like the self-help section
and discover like the self-development
books in in the library i was like
whoa i get to like learn things that i
didn't get it you know i didn't have it
my dad didn't teach me these things that
other people got to get got to be taught
so i get to learn them i i uh so
uh oh man how would i be less selfish
with what i was trying to say
um i
s self-help i'm not trying to to defend
self-help
i feel like that's where i fell into um
but i do i do see like the self-help um
there's a lot of different ways there's
a lot of different
rivers that lead to the same lake and i
think
that germany yeah yeah but
so so okay so so the the common common
common ground here
is uh is choosing a like just following
a path like whatever if it means that
you read 100 self-help books that's cool
but if it
means you read six and you get the gist
of it that's cool too but follow
a path towards self-improvement
self-betterment
and trust that your path is the right
path for you
yeah but i will say a fair word to the
i will warn everyone this so in america
a lot of the self-help that is written
is strictly for corporate productivity
that's it it's just how do you be more
productive
and i think that that is really missing
the forest
through the trees on that because we are
just like a
hyper productive society more than
anywhere else that is top of mind for
for most people is how do i get more out
of my 40 hour work week that is probably
too long anyways
and that i firmly believe that is not
actually
really self-help at that point in time
yeah you're more productive but
did you learn anything about reality or
yourself or come to any conclusions no
you just learned how to focus for longer
which is good
that's good you know it's a helpful
skill but it's not
actually self-help i really don't think
so not in the way that i would like
others to engage with so i i would look
to eastern philosophies
probably not not western south western
self-help is like tim ferriss telling
you you need to hire a secretary to do
your busy work
yeah i like that you just made this
definitive line between this and i
really like that you brought it into
like western self-help versus easter
self-help
because i'm definitely one who i have
very much dove and into
this western like productivity uh a lot
like the garyvee sort of stuff even like
you can you can even take some sort of
like the spiritual law of attraction
sort of stuff
and apply it into that same realm of
that self-help um
but but there also is this other side of
like you're kind of
eastern philosophy is like the uh uh uh
eastern self-help is like the um
self-help of philosophy it's itself like
uh
it's just like slow mindful and
introspective
and causes you to not be hyperproductive
and that's actually a good thing like
hyper productivity will actually detract
from self-actualization because you're
spending too much time
just generating gold and that is like
fundamentally at odds with all of the
stuff that self-help would really drive
and it also sometimes creates this uh
this problem of i think alan watts calls
it the backwards law
basically by being someone that needs to
improve by being someone who needs to do
these things you're now
identifying with someone of lack you're
that you're identifying as
like the the negative aspect the into
the yang of the thing that you're trying
to achieve
and you're you're living through that
like i am a person who
needs to do this so that i can be
happier
so that i can feel this you know
completion or whatever well
and the win condition for society is to
be really productive too the way it's
set up not to be slow and mindful
you know so be like learning how to be
this
actually puts you fundamentally at odds
with how we've constructed our economic
system
which is to be giga productive just
get make as much money as you can for
someone else and kind of yourself
and that is the opposite of the we need
to
really slow down really introspect and
really think about our surroundings and
i think that's the big rift because like
gary vee like hustle culture self-help
i think is pretty harmful not helpful
mm-hmm
yeah that's that's like uh that's like
the pickup
culture versus psychology you know like
psychology is good but if you're using
it just for
uh picking up women like you're kind of
missing the
missing the point here yeah yeah
cool well all right i mean i feel like i
mean i feel like we did
point to a lot of the important things
on here um
where where are we at for you spencer
what do you think how do you think we
did on defining
explaining um just addressing cancer
culture from where it's really at like
it's
it's kind of hard like what exactly
we're answering what is cancer culture
and why does it affect us blah blah blah
but
how is this information useful to the
average
consumer um like why is this something
that is
important and what else what do we need
to reiterate or or
cover still on this castle culture
subject do we do our thing
uh i think so i don't know if this got
clipped but i just
really want people to be wary when
they're seeing like
a lot of if it's political cancer
culture
like rhetoric just either one somebody
just having an idea and then getting
criticism
and then not liking criticism and saying
this is cancer culture because that does
happen
pretty frequently it's like if you are
have a political id in a public space
like the point is that it's up to
scrutiny that's just what happens
that's how it goes like if you're a
large figure like
your ideas have been put out there to
scrutinize this is politics you've
chosen to engage with this that's how it
is
so i wouldn't i would be it's just a bad
excuse
to reject criticism is instead of
actually having to hone your ideas
against someone else's you just say no
they're just trying to cancel me you're
being too woke
here it is so it insulates criticism
number one
i think it's important to recognize that
because it's allowed some people to live
in a space where they never actually
like have to elaborate or deal with any
of their ideas
they just point to the big scary word
and people are like oh
yeah you're right that is cancer culture
uh what else um
i want people to be wary of when
something is happening especially with
social progress and people are labeling
it as woke
cancer culture to really look at the
underlying subtext of the situation so
when a rights are revoked or when like
when anything bad happens to any
minority groups or any
i mean just any people in general nobody
really talks about it but
like when trans people want better
rights
when black people want better voting
laws
that don't systemically oppress them
it's all of a sudden
this is woke and authoritarian so be
careful
at the narrative that is being displayed
by people in power
when it is obviously conflicting their
power structures
like nobody gets mad at the i mean
people get mad at the catholic church
but the catholic church has been doing
pretty authoritarian cancer culture
stuff forever
people really talk about it it's because
it's only when
the ideas really brush up against
the current power structures that there
is a massive fit thrown
and you should look at that friction and
like hey
maybe there's something to this maybe
there's not maybe there's a group of
people that is actually being
unreasonable
but it's subject for inspection
my but my biggest worry of all time
definitely
is the label woke and the label cancel
culture
is just being used to stop civil rights
from progressing
it's just stopping it yeah so like if
you can use some
niche problem that nobody cares about to
uh red herring or take attention away
from like real problems i'm pretty sure
i mentioned this on the uh
the pre-pod but trans people have a life
expectancy between 30 and 35
but media outlets are trying to force
trans bathroom bills is the problem
and these actually are just people that
are really scrutinized ostracized and
hated on in society
and nobody asked for this you know
same with voting laws like stuff like
that it's just there is a red herring
a social friction that is being thrown
in front of you
to distract you from some real big
systemic problems
and causing infighting when we actually
can probably agree on a lot of it
so just be fair warned when you hear any
of the hot button words
when you hear post-modern neo-marxist
um critical race theory like like a lot
of these words that seem really buzzy
whoa
cancer culture not saying that the
person that is saying them
is in bad faith or uh is necessarily
been wrong it's just subject to
inspection
yeah i mean i i like that i was thinking
about how we uh
our culture inevitably wants to memify
everything we want to like you know
condense it down to to these ideologies
um and we're so fast-paced and our
attention spans are so quick that we
just like oh yeah
uh you know woke-ism or neo-marxism and
we completely
think we understand it we just blaze for
the next thing because we want to really
condense it all down to one thing get on
to the next thing
um but yeah i think yeah introspectively
looking at these things
uh questioning them um not
not falling into the trap of like
talking about it all the time i think
i think that's what's going to happen is
canceled culture is going to fizzle out
like meaning i think it already yeah i
think
i think you're you're right there i mean
it's uh
it's it's feels like this was something
we were talking about for a while
and it feels so much less important than
just a couple months ago i'm like dude
yeah it's just
it's a it's a whatever i don't care
about it yeah and just
a lot of times in the news cycle a it's
a red herring
these social issues so like a few months
ago when the amazon strikes were
happening they hired off-duty police
officers to break union rallies and then
they illegally voted against the union
inside to not allow workers to get
rights
but if you look in that time there was
more than likely some other social drama
meaningless dribble that was thrown in
front of the public eye
to distract from this real thing that's
happening
so yeah i mean that that is a bigger
problem in general like media really is
going to start
um i mean it start it's going to
continue to cause a lot of havoc and
destruction
in our society if it's not i don't know
if putin
check is the correct um phrase to use
but
we do need to do something different
about our not just the media by itself
but even
how we consume media and what we what we
care about and talk about and think
about
yeah and with uh my one last thing that
i would hope people would do
is um now that old media is dying and
there's no authoritarian place you will
go to youtube
you'll go to these other places where
you can hear anyone talk about anything
and i would really really really be
careful
at who you give your time to and who
you're listening to as a definitive
source
because a lot of times like i said
before we have a lot of these
unconscious bias
we have a lot of these things that we
just innately believe and subconsciously
when we hear something that we might
agree with
but with a little extra flavor into it
we're just gonna
we're just gonna go right to that but
really really inspect
what people are actually saying like if
somebody's making a claim
make sure that they support it
understand what is being claimed
and decide if you agree with the
conclusion don't let other people think
for you
like you'll see it and just like a lot
of uh really just new sites in general
you'll somebody will force you to see
a problem through their world view and
then come up with a
lens or solution that is favorable to
their cause
so just hey what is this person what is
the claim
and what is the elaboration and
conclusion of this claim
yeah okay and i think one more important
thing is just to go back to the
entertainment versus like news
and how it's been all meshed together
entertainment versus things that are
very important i think
observe how your mind listens like if
you're listening to someone like me
i'm not someone who's ever claiming to
be like the arbiter of absolute facts
i don't know exactly what's going on i'm
someone who i stumble through my
thinking in real time
um and i think that listening to me in
the exact same way that you would listen
to
you know let's say someone that an
important news acre
who's giving you something that's
supposed to be considered as fact
um i think it you listen to them a bit
differently
like there is an openness that you need
to bring into casual conversation
versus this uh reality overlay that we
have
of our of our news and them saying hey
here's what's going on
and here's what we know about it and
here's what you should do about it those
are things that maybe you should be
uh um you know questioning at the very
least
yeah so yeah just that definitive line
between entertainment and
this wasn't so bad spencer no i think we
uh
we did all right we definitely touched
on a lot more than i thought we were
going to today but
that's how it's going to be and i just
for sure enjoyed it
yeah it was good stuff i feel like we uh
i feel like we can kind of put cancer
culture to bed i mean i know we always
like dabbling into anything when it
comes to
mind viruses or just any sort of sense
making sickness
um or inability to sense make as a
general
population we're always going to love
talking about those sorts of things and
we will continue to talk about those
sorts of things but
i'm thinking that this cancel culture
thing can be put into the back seat
yeah i mean i never really i've never
looked at it as really problematic
i think now more than ever it is i mean
it might have been a problem maybe five
years ago but this is so
far beyond the scope of society and what
people are actually worried about or any
of these groups that you're scared of or
heard bad things about or focusing on
that it's just uh
this is a complete red herring and
non-issue and for people personally
don't worry about it don't worry about
it just work on being a good person
forget about it just focus on yourself
take care of yourself who else is going
to do that all right dude um well i
i appreciate you i appreciate your brain
i appreciate your thoughts i appreciate
your time
um i i always love uh having chats with
you
and i'm grateful that you're you're
willing to come on to the podcast
and express your your feelings and
thoughts and
and ideas and uh i mean undoubtedly
helping people
you know that's that's what we're here
to do is try to help people
understand uh not saying that we are
correct we're
right but kind of just i like saying the
ushers of
epiphany so i like to uh our
conversations i feel like they point to
things within other people's minds that
they can then go
oh huh i don't even think about it that
way cool and maybe your life's a little
bit better
because of it so i appreciate you maybe
truth isn't real
but we're going to think about stuff
anyways
yeah there is no capital t in truth but
we're going to look for it anyway
all right all right jake welcome yeah um
listeners have a good rest your day as
usual drink a lot of water if you're not
drinking a ton of water today
you're a big dummy um and i hope you get
canceled
so take care of yourself love yourself
stretch
uh spencer uh do you have any content
online yet that you want to direct
people towards yeah
okay uh everybody message spencer and
tell him that you want him to create his
own channel
because uh he has an important mind and
perspective on these topics
and i would listen to it myself to be
honest so i mean
and if you have any um questions about
left-leaning political views or anything
that i've discussed today or anything
you want me to elaborate on you can
find me on instagram at spencer hicks
underscore
for sure just shoot me a message i'll be
happy to partly with you
and even if you uh disagree with
everything he says and he thinks and you
think that
um you want to debate the guy let me
know
and i'll be like all right i'll i will
be the middleman of this debate via this
podcast if it's i mean if i do deem it
to be
uh important and valuable i think that
would actually be kind of fun
so cool all right spencer i love and
appreciate you i'll text you just here
in a little bit
and uh listeners i love and appreciate
you just as well and uh i won't text you
but i thank you for listening to the
podcast and take care of yourself
goodbye
and don't forget to breathe don't forget
to breathe breathe from your belly
to diaphragm and your nasal cavity
[Music]
goodbye
knowledge is power
[Music]